# KOFI OHEMENG NTIKORAH

#### **Geospatial Data analyst**

Accra

ohemengk95@gmail.com

+233 54 291 0178

A GIS ANALYST equipped with workflow automation skills. Proven experience in the geospatial sector with experience in sourcing data and generating insights for industry decisions. Adaptable, analytical, creative and a team player. I am a fast learner, I try to explore in order to understand company processes and best practices . Seek to promote company net ratio and be of value wherever I find myself.

GIS project Repository:https://github.com/kof1nti

GIS portfolio: https://github.com/kof1nti/nearest/blob/b7e7784ca78167f50b05ecf614b5a4387c8d7976/GIS%20PORTFOLIO\_Kofi%20Ohemeng%20Ntikorah.pdf

## Work Experience

#### **GIS Analyst**

Walulel - Accra May 2018 to Present

- Set up a spatial data pipeline which automates metric analysis in the area of demographics, built environment, amenities using drake, an R studio library.
- Built a model in QGIS for metric workflow. Datasets analysed were air quality, conservation areas, urban islands, schools, opportunity areas, house price, transport, congestion charge zones. These metrics were analysed to be embedded on Walnsight, a location intelligent software platform for London.
- Collaborated with developers, UI/UX designers by ensuring features for web and mobile versions of applications were developed. Features such as geolocation grid to track user behaviour, proximity analysis to define customer radius were developed.
- Prepared technical documents on application reviews.
- Liaised with Jas Bhalla Architects to prepare heatmaps for affordable housing designs. Jas Bhalla Architects and Walulel won the 2019 William Sutton Prize.
- Ensure scripts are written for upcoming metrics and existing codes reviewed and maintained.
- Developed models for geospatial analysis. Models to track London alternative postcodes, area friendliness and environmental analysis were developed in QGIS.

## Geospatial data sourcing expert/Analyst

Freelancer

June 2021 to August 2021

• Sourced geospatial data in the area of built environment, demographics, amenities which can be used to build a location intelligent platform. I ensured that data sourced were accurate and to the right standard when used for data analysis.

- I validated data offerings from mobility data providers. Meetings were scheduled with providers, data needs were presented and feedbacks were documented accordingly. This ensured data offerings were understood and reviewed.
- A report of data needs, consideration and recommendations was presented. This report served as a guide for development of a location intelligent product.

## Python GIS developer/Machine Learning

Freelancer

June 2021 to August 2021

- I tutored on using QGIS and machine learning with focus on applying algorithms to detect weeds in a plantation. This was achieved by building a detection algorithm using dzetsaka and semi-automatic classification plugin incorporating random forest, SVM and GMM models.
- Aided trainee in setting up a git hub page website and pages to visualise web map composed in QGIS.
- Introduced trainee to anaconda, jupyter notebook and python libraries such as open cv, tensor flow, geopandas. A detection model was developed to detect weeds in a plantation.

#### **GIS Data Scientist**

Safegraph

July 2021 to July 2021

- Evaluated places data by bringing context to advertisement and understanding navigation of customers.
- Spatial analysis and data science were applied to contextualize these two use cases, navigation and advertisement. A report which makes a robust places data for Canada, US and Britain was presented.

#### Cartographer, Data Visualisation expert

Freelancer

January 2020 to May 2021

- As a cartographer, I have composed static maps which depict study areas. Some of these maps show forest reserves, wetlands, settlements. Geoprocessing algorithms were applied to present fine visualisations. https://github.com/kof1nti/nearest
- Web map of a suburb in Ghana showing 100m grids has been visualised to provide insight into geolocation. https://kof1nti.github.io/numero.github.io/
- Web map showing planning policy of Greater London has been visualised. This map provides meaning into urban planning. https://kof1nti.github.io/webpolicy/

#### Surveyor

Joeamah Geomatic Consult - Accra June 2017 to August 2017

- As part of an asset mapping project of the Electricity Company of Ghana, I mapped metred and non-metred assets including houses, electric poles.
- With the aid of an automatic level, total station and drones, setting out surveys and detailing were done for a section of Ridge Hospital as part of a phase two project. In the end a misclose and an accuracy were achieved.
- Ground truthing a part in Accra was done to ensure map produced was accurate. Omissions and errors were duly noted and applied.

#### **Surveyor and CAD expert**

Survey and Mapping Division May 2015 to August 2015

- Prepared new site plans for land owners. This was done to ensure owners had the updated site plans in lieu of old ones. Auto cad was used in preparing site plans.
- · Demarcated plots of lands.
- Prepared and compiled survey reports to be signed by Regional Surveyors. I ensured checks were done and corrected of errors.

#### Education

### **BSc in Geomatic Engineering**

KNUST - Ashanti Region August 2014 to May 2018

## Skills

 ArcGIS, QGIS,R, PYTHON, POSTGRESQL, GITHUB, GOOGLE EARTH,REMOTE SENSING, EXCEL, PowerBI, Tableau, Geoda,Photomodeller,AWS,MACHINE LEARNING, data science,data scraping, data collection, data analytics, data analysis, data modelling, data processing, product evaluation, data visualisation, writing, research, product management, slack, click up, microsoft teams (4 years)

## Languages

- English Fluent
- Twi Fluent

## Certifications and Licenses

### Going places with spatial analysis

January 2019 to March 2019

Issued by ESRI by attending the MOOC